ANDREW WITHERSPOON

DeForest, WI, 53532

C: +1 (608) 960-1482

abethel1986@outlook.com

Summary

Over the last six years, I have written software and web applications both as part of my own company/service in China, and for startups in both China and the United States. I have acquired a lengthy set of experience, and never forgotten to take the extra time to train and stay on top of the latest technologies in the programming world. I have acted as team lead and project manager on numerous projects, and have always brought projects to completion on or ahead of deadlines.

Education

Coder Camps - Development Bootcamp

• ~1500 hours of development experience with C# and JavaScript

Madison Area Technical College - Fire/EMS

- Firefighter I/II
- NREMT-B, WI EMT-B

Skillset

- C#, JavaScript (including Node, AngularJS, ReactJS, jQuery, ES6, TypeScript), HTML, CSS, LESS/SASS, SQL, Git, Webpack, Gulp, mobile frameworks such as Ionic, Cordova/PhoneGap
- *NIX, Windows

Portfolio

• Visit http://awitherspoon.github.io to view my personal page and go over example algorithm code snippets, or read code from my repositories at http://github.com/awitherspoon

Experience

Senior Engineer

Hardin Design & Development

April 2016 - Present

- Fixing broken projects so they are maintainable and cloneable
- Project lead on GIS software project in cooperation with American Family Insurance and MapLarge
- Crafting new UI and server-side data ingest system for above project
- Mentor for junior developers

Technologies: Javascript (ES2015), Python, MySQL, PostgreSQL, React, Node

Front End Engineer

Strikingly

June 2015 - December 2015

- Built robust APIs and UI components for Strikingly's website builder product
- Conversion of Angular/Knockout components and templates to React components
- Redesign of themes and editor UI/UX
- Work on new mobile editor for iOS devices, dynamically async loading UI components

<u>Technologies:</u> React/AngularJS, ES2015, jQuery, Webpack, Ruby, LESS, HTML5, PostgreSQL

Classroom Assistant

Coder For Rent

May 2015 – June 2015

- Built a WPF application (C# and XAML) using the Kinect for Windows 2.0 and Windows Speech SDK's for better attendance tracking
- Assisted instructor with new students

Technologies: C#, XAML, jQuery, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, SQL

Foreign Manager

Assorted companies/Self

October 2011 – January 2015

- Wrote browser based training applications for use on local intranets to ensure higher quality training for new foreign staff
- Ensured teaching quality was high and amended curriculum as necessary for touchscreen based delivery platforms

Technologies: HTML, JavaScript/jQuery, CSS, Flash